SHAMEEN SHETTY

706 W MITCHELL CIR APT 0618 Arlington Tx · (862) 289-7196
shettyshameen1@gmail.com ·
https://www.linkedin.com/in/shameen-shetty-7648791a4/ ·
https://github.com/ShameenShetty/

Computer Engineering Undergraduate. Interested in learning new languages to further knowledge in programming and learn new concepts that may have not been used in previous languages. Good team experience and time and project management. Bringing programming experience and expertise in Python, Java, C, and Rust. I believe my fast learning abilities, commitment to deepen my knowledge in programming, and relevant courses taken make me the perfect fit for most programming jobs.

EXPERIENCE

MAY 2016 – AUG 2016 INTERN, NEUROLINX

• Learnt more about Java, MySQL during my Internship, and used that knowledge to help build a Portal for a product – Chicken ERP or ChERP.

AUG 2019 - NOV 2019

DEVELOPER, UTA CSE-3310 TEAM PROJECT

- Worked on an Android application for my CSE3310 Final Project building a SMS (ServeMe System) using Waterfall Approach.
- Tasks were split equally amongst team-members.
- Helped provide the UML diagrams for Login & Registration, Order History, and Search.
- Helped write the requirements for Login & Registration, Order History, and Search.
- Helped in creating parts of the application, using Android Studio.
- GitHub link: https://github.com/ShameenShetty/CSE-3310--Final Project

FEB 3, 2020 - FEB 17, 2020

SOLE DEVELOPER, UTA CSE-3320 PROJECT

- Wrote a Shell program in C, which can implement basic commands that other shells have (for example, 'ls' command or 'cd dirName'.
- GitHub link: https://github.com/ShameenShetty/CSE-3320--Assignment-1-Shell

JAN 2020 - MAY 2020

SOLE DEVELOPER, UTA CSE-2441 PROJECT

- Built a Tiny Reduced Instruction Set Computer (TRISC) Controller as the final project for the CSE-2441 course. Used basic building blocks that were shown in Labs 1 to 8 and combined them to build the final Controller in Lab 9. The TRISC unit takes input from the user, decodes it using the Instruction Decoder (ID), and outputs that result to the Controller.
- Coded the Controller in Verilog, which can execute six instructions INC, CLR, JMP, LDA, STA, and ADD (Increment ACC, Clear ACC, Jump, Load ACC, Store ACC, and Add ACC instructions), and completed the bonus part where I combined the Instruction

Decoder and Six Instruction Controller and demonstrated it on the DE1 Altera Board to the teacher

EDUCATION

2017 - CURRENT

COMPUTER ENGINEERING UNDERGRAD, UTA

- Member of National Society of Collegiate Scholars (NSCS)
- Awarded \$2,000 Maverick Academic Scholarship
- Relevant coursework:
 - o Algorithms & Data Structures
 - Object Oriented Programming
 - o Programming Languages
 - o Linear Algebra for Computer Science
 - o Intro to Signal Processing
 - Database System and File Structures
- Managed student projects to:
 - o Implement a basic shell in C
 - o Build a 'Baby Shazam' program in Python
 - Work with a small team to create an Android Application for small businesses or homeowners using Waterfall Method
 - Build a project for CSE3330 for a real-life application Project Trash, which aims to solve the problem of Online Apparel Return Induced Trash. Done using MySQL and PHP for the website.

SKILLS

Python

Java

Rust

• C

MySQL

Problem Solving

Analytical Skills

Attention to detail

Project Management

Teamwork

Work Ethic

• Time Management

HOBBIES

Interested about computers, and programming in general – I like learning about new and interesting coding languages – apart from the languages that were taught in my courses, learnt a new programming language (Rust) as I found it very interesting. Worked in a startup company and worked on many projects for my classes – further details are given my GitHub profile. Currently watching Corey Schafer's videos for tutorials on Python, as well as reading 'Automate the Boring Stuff' by Al Sweigart.